Guide to the Robert Pinsky Papers
Department of Special Collections
Robert Pinsky Papers
Special Collections M0697
Pinsky, Robert
19 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions:
Materials generated from Jan. 1996 on are partially restricted. Please enquire.
Provenance:
Purchased by Stanford University Libraries from Robert Pinsky, April, 1994. Addenda received after 1994 are part of purchase agreement.
BIOGRAPHY
Robert Pinsky, poet and literary critic, was born in 1940 in Long Beach, New Jersey. He studied English at Rutgers University (B.A., 1962) and Stanford University (M.A. and Ph.D., 1967). He has taught at the University of Chicago (1966-67), Wellesley College (1967-1980), and the University of California, Berkeley (1980-present). Since 1979, Pinsky has been poetry editor for The New Republic.
Pinsky has published two volumes of poetry: Sadness And Happiness (1975) and An Explanation of America (1979). His other major works are Landor's Poetry (1968)-a revision of his Ph.D. dissertation, The Situation of Poetry (1977)-a discussion of "this current moment" in modern poetry, and a verse translation of Dante's Inferno (1995). Pinsky's literary criticism also includes articles written for various periodicals and a large number of book reviews for the Los Angeles Times.
SCOPE AND CONTENT
The Pinsky Papers is a collection of 19 linear feet of materials relating to the life and literary work of Robert Pinsky. The collection includes his personal and professional correspondence, poetry, literary criticism, and academic notes and papers. Also included are published and unpublished works by other poets, newspaper clippings and other memorabilia, as well as galley proofs for three of Pinsky's most recent books.
ARRANGEMENT NOTE
The Robert Pinsky Papers includes several ADDENDA, each containing correspondence, manuscripts, and other materials pertaining to Pinsky's life and career. The materials are organized within each addendum, but are not interfiled; that is, materials that came together from the author remain together. Therefore, Pinsky's poetry (for example) can be found in several different locations throughout the collection-in boxes 4-8 (original collection), 15-16 (Addendum 1), 19a-20 (Addendum 2), 20-21 (Addendum 3), 27 (Addendum 4), and 33 (Addenda 5 and 6). To ensure a thorough viewing of the entire contents of any given series or subseries, please consult the ENTIRE container listing for each series and/or CONSULT SPECIAL COLLECTIONS STAFF.
Due to varying contents and time lapses between addenda, organization varies throughout the collection. Due to the nature of the collection, there is a great deal of overlap between series. For example, personal correspondence often contains poetry; some poetry files include correspondence and miscellany filed by Pinsky as "source material"; items from various categories are often filed together as they came from Pinsky or as is most logical. To avoid overlooking relevant materials, researchers should peruse the guide and browse the entire collection.
Additional materials are still arriving from Pinsky, often in small installments. These addenda will be organized as they are received and added at the end of the collection. Check with Special Collections staff for contents updates.
Processor: September, 1996
SERIES DESCRIPTION
- Series I. Correspondence:
  This series consists of alphabetically arranged personal and professional correspondence. In the original collection, correspondence from relatives (including Pinsky's parents, grandparents, and siblings) is filed together. Other major personal correspondence includes letters from other contemporary writers such as David Bromwich, Alan Cheuse, Donald Davie, Digby Diehl, Edwin Honig, James McMichael, and John Peck. The professional correspondence is alphabetized by organization or topic. Under The New Republic correspondence are both Pinsky's correspondence with the magazine and drafts of poetry submitted to Pinsky in his position as poetry editor, organized alphabetically by author. Another large section of professional correspondence consists of Pinsky's files on his poetry readings, arranged by the names of the host institutions. Corrspeondence in the addenda is generally kept all together, organized alphabetically by last name or institution name, and occasionally by subject.
- Series II. Poetry:
  Drafts of Pinsky's Sadness And Happiness and An Explanation of America are arranged in order of refinement, from the first draft to the final manuscript. The drafts of Sadness And Happiness are listed under various titles as the book progresses, and all copies of poems which have been deleted are to be found following the draft in which they last appeared. The drafts of An Explanation of America are organized according to the internal sections of the book itself. Miscellaneous poetry is arranged alphabetically by title. Translations by Pinsky (of work by Boris Christov and Czeslaw Milosz, and of Dante's Infemo) are also inluded.
- Series III. Criticism:
  Included in this series are articles by Pinsky, as well as book reviews for the Los Angeles Times, arranged alphabetically by the last name of the author being reviewed. The notes, drafts, and revisions of The Situation of Poetry are organized by chapters, in order of refinement.
- Series IV. Academic Papers:
  These undergraduate and graduate papers and notes remain in the order in which Pinsky arranged them. Major papers included are his undergraduate honors thesis, "The Plays of T. S. Eliot," and his graduate thesis, "The Poetry of Walter Savage Landor." Materials from Pinsky's 1981 trip to Eastern Europe are also included in this series.
- Series V. Memorabilia:
  The items in this series include invitations to readings, newspaper clippings, and other miscellaneous material.
- Series VI. Poetry and Prose by Other Writers:
  Included in this series are published and unpublished works by other writers, sent to Pinsky by his friends and former students. This includes large quantities of work by poets such as Frank Bidart, Carl Dennis, David Ferry, Barry Goldensohn, Donald Hall, Robert Hass, John Hollander, Kathryn Hellerstein, James McMichael, Lloyd Scwartz, and David Thorburn.
- Series VII. Galley Proofs and Oversized:
  Included in this series are oversized materials and the galley proofs for Pinsky's three most recent books.
- Series VIII. Interviews:
  This series consists of interviews with Pinsky.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Subseries: General
    - A, misc.:
      - Agenda (Michael Collier) (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Allen, Dick (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - The American Poetry Review (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - The American Review (Richard Howard) (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - American Scholar (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Antæus (Daniel Halpern) (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Arion (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Ascent (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Ashbery, John (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Ashbury Park Press (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Aswell, Duncan (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - The Atlantic Monthly (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - B, misc.:
      - Babb, Howard (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Bailey, Sam (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Barth, Fred (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Bates, Karen (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Baum, Beth (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Bedient, Calvin (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Beloit Journal (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Bernstein, Richard (Pepper, Hamilton & Sheetz) (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Black, Helene [?] (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Boston Public Library (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - boundary 2 (William Spanos/Philip Dow) (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Brandeis University (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Braude, Ben (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Burns, Gerald (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Blacksmith Poetry Newsletter (Gail Mazur, Judith Baumel) (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Boston Magazine/Boston Phoenix (Diane McWhorter) (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Bromwich, David (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - C, misc.:
      - The Clarendon Prefs (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Cameron, John (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Carnochan, Brigitte (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Children's Literary Association (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Chowder Review (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - College English (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Counter/Measures (X.J. Kennedy) (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Cunningham, J.V. (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Cheuse, Alan (and Marjorie Pryce) (Box 1, Folder 7.1)
      - Chicago Review (Timothy Erwin) (Box 1, Folder 7.2)
      - Crenshaw, Brad and Debra Gorlin (Box 1, Folder 7.3)
    - D, misc.:
      - De Porte, Mike (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Denver Quarterly (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Dougherty, Monica (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Driecoll, Phil (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Dufours Editions, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Dale, Peter (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Davie, Donald (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Diehl, Digby (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - E-F, misc.:
      - Epstein, E.L. (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Esquire (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Estess, Sybil (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Ezell, Margaret (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Field (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Fields, Ken (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Fifer, Norma (Mrs. Charles) (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Fellowship applications (Pinsky) (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Fitzgerald, Robert (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Fussell, Paul (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - G, misc.:
      - Galassi, Jonathan (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Glascock Poetry Contest (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Goddard College (Michael Ryan) (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Graff, Gerald (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Green, Cindy (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Gross, Harvey (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - H-I, misc.:
      - Hadas, Rachel (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Hair, Elizabeth (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Hall, Donald (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Halliday, Mark (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Halperin, Mark (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Ham, ? (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Hamilton, Ian (and Eric Kurtz) (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Hamilton, Ralph (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Harper's (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Harvard: Houghton Library (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Hecht, Anthony (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Heifetz, Harriet and Elmer (The Cathy Heifetz Memorial, University of Chicago) (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Holland, Albert (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Houghton Mifflin Co. (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Howard, Dee (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Howard, Olga (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Howard, Richard (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Howe, Irving (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - The Hudson Review (Frederick Morgan) (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Indiana University Press (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Harcourt Brace Jovanich, Inc. (William Pullin) (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Hass, Robert (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - Hellerstein, Kathryn (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Honig, Edwin (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - J-L, misc.:
      - Jackson, Tom (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Kayak (George Hitchcock) (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Kaitz, Merrill (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Kennikat Press Corp. (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Kuzma, Greg (The Best Cellar Press) (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - L=A=N=G=U=A=G=E (Charles Bernstein) (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Lentrenkin, Frank (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Lewis (Winters), Janet (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Leysorek, Myra (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - The Little Square Review (John Ridland) (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Los Angeles Times Book Review (Art Seidenbaum) (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Kenyon College/Honors Candidate Examiner (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Louisiana State University Press (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - M, misc.:
      - Mahoney, Linda (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Maniquis, Felixberto (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Mariani, Paul (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Massachusetts Review (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Mazur, Gail (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Melone, Debbie (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Merfeld, Patricia (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Michigan Quarterly Review (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Miklitsch, Robert (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Modern Occasions (Philip Rahv) (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - McGann, Jerome (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - McMichael, James, 1965-1970 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - McMichael, James, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - McMichael, James, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - McMichael, James, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Modern Language Association (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - N, misc.:
      - The Nation (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - The New England Review (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - The New Review (Ian Hamilton) (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - The New York Quarterly (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - The New Yorker (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - The New York Times Book Review (Harvey Shapiro) (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Newcomb, Sue (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - The North American Review (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Najarian, Peter (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Najarian, Peter, incl. "The Prism" (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - O, misc.:
      - Oliver, Ray (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - O'Neill, Ellen (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - O Press (Michael Lally) (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - P, misc.:
      - The Painted Bird Quarterly (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - The Paris Review (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Parkinson, Thomas (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - The Partisan Review (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Peters, Robert and Carol Yeh (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Pinskey, Raleigh (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Pinsky, Robert to "Gene" (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Plishner, Emily (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Powell, Grosvenor (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Proudfit, Charles (English Language Notes) (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Pym, A. Gordon (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Parnassus (Herb Leibowitz) (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Peck, John, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Peck, John, 1967-1970 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Peck, John, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Peck, John, 1873-1978 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Peseroff, Joyce (Greenhouse) (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Ploughshares (DeWitt Henry) (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Poetry Magazine (Daryl Hine, M. Shea, Dick Allen) (Box 3a, Folder 1)
      - Poetry Readings (Pinsky): (Box 3a, Folder 2)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: Allegheny (Al Kern) (Box 3a, Folder 2)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: Amherst College (Howell Chickering) (Box 3a, Folder 2)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: Boston Public Library ("Literary Boston" series) (Box 3a, Folder 2)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: Blacksmith Poetry Newsletter (Gail Mazur) (Box 3a, Folder 2)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: Brandeis University series for Prof. J.V. Cunningham (Allen Grossman) (Box 3a, Folder 2)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: California Institute of the Arts (Susan Baumann) (Box 3a, Folder 2)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: Cambridge Street Artists' Cooperative (Marjorie Fletcher) (Box 3a, Folder 2)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: College of Staten Island (Herb Leibowitz) (Box 3a, Folder 2)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: Connecticut Poetry Circuit (incl. Jean Maynard, Dick Allen) (Box 3a, Folder 3)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: Dartmouth College (Jay Parini) (Box 3a, Folder 4)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: Ferguson Library (Kathy Galomb) (Box 3a, Folder 4)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: Hathaway House (Robert Hale) (Box 3a, Folder 4)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: New England Review (Box 3a, Folder 4)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: New York University (Walter J. Miller) (Box 3a, Folder 4)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: Northern Essex Community College (Box 3a, Folder 4)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: The Poetry Center (Betsy Dunn, Grace Schulman) (Box 3a, Folder 4)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: Princeton Library in New York (Box 3a, Folder 5)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: Princeton University (Jack Talbott) (Box 3a, Folder 5)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: Rutgers College (Alan Nadel) (Box 3a, Folder 5)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: St. Olaf College (Box 3a, Folder 5)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: Stanford University (incl. Ken Fields) (Box 3a, Folder 5)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: SUNY, Buffalo (Carl Dennis) (Box 3a, Folder 5)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: University of Bridgeport (Box 3a, Folder 6)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: University of California, Berkeley (Box 3a, Folder 6)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: University of California, Los Angeles (Box 3a, Folder 6)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: University of California, Santa Barbara (Box 3a, Folder 6)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: University of Chicago (Box 3a, Folder 7)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: University of Tennessee (Marjorie Pryce) (Box 3a, Folder 7)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: Vanderbilt University (Box 3a, Folder 8)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: Vassar College (Box 3a, Folder 8)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: Wellesley College (Box 3a, Folder 8)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: WGBH Radio (Box 3a, Folder 8)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: Williams College (Garry [?]) (Box 3a, Folder 8)
      - Pinsky Poetry Readings: Miscellaneous notes from readings (Box 3a, Folder 8)
      - Poetry readings at Wellesley by others (incl. Archie Ammons, John Ashbery, Ted and Renée Weiss, Jay Wright) (Box 3a, Folder 9)
      - Poetry Wales (John Ward) (Box 3a, Folder 10)
      - Princeton University Press (Mrs. Arthur "Jerry" Sherwood) (Box 3a, Folder 11)
    - Q-R, misc.:
      - Quarterly Review of Literature (Ted and Renée Weiss) (Box 3a, Folder 12)
      - Ramke, Bin (Box 3a, Folder 12)
      - Ransom, Dave (Box 3a, Folder 12)
      - Rector, Liam (Box 3a, Folder 12)
      - Reed, Linda (Box 3a, Folder 12)
      - Reeve, Franklin (Box 3a, Folder 12)
      - Reid, Randall (Box 3a, Folder 12)
      - Ridland, John (Box 3a, Folder 12)
      - Roberts, June (a.k.a. Habiba Abdullah) (Box 3a, Folder 12)
      - Rutledge, Ann (Box 3a, Folder 12)
      - Reappointments and Promotions Committee, Wellesley (Box 3a, Folder 13)
    - S, misc.:
      - Salmagundi (Bob Boyers) (Box 3a, Folder 14)
      - Sands, Bob (Box 3a, Folder 14)
      - Saturday Review (Susan Heath) (Box 3a, Folder 14)
      - Shenandoah (Dabney Stuart) (Box 3a, Folder 14)
      - Spacks, Barry (Box 3a, Folder 14)
      - Spacks, Patricia (Box 3a, Folder 14)
      - Stein, Dona (Box 3a, Folder 14)
      - Sussna, Robert (Box 3a, Folder 14)
      - Swanberg, Judy (Box 3a, Folder 14)
      - Schwartz, Lloyd (Box 3a, Folder 15)
      - Seneca Review (Albert Golbarth) (Box 3a, Folder 16)
      - Sheidley, Bill and Harlow (Box 3a, Folder 17)
      - Southern Review (Donald Stanford) (Box 3a, Folder 18)
      - Stand (incl. Edward Brunner) (Box 3a, Folder 19)
    - T-U, misc.:
      - Talbott, Jack (Box 3a, Folder 20)
      - Tennis World (Box 3a, Folder 20)
      - Tien, Adrienne (Box 3a, Folder 20)
      - Tri-Quarterly (Box 3a, Folder 20)
      - Tsiáras, Phillip (Box 3a, Folder 20)
      - University of California Press (Leonard Michaels) (Box 3a, Folder 20)
      - University of Chicago Press (Allen N. Fitchen) (Box 3a, Folder 20)
      - Thorburn, David (Box 3a, Folder 21)
      - Tufts University/Experimental College (Box 3a, Folder 22)
      - University of Massachusetts Press (Hanna Hoppre: 1979 Juniper Prize) (Box 3a, Folder 23)
    - V-Z, misc.:
      - Virginia Quarterly Review (Box 3a, Folder 24)
      - von Hallberg, Robert (Box 3a, Folder 24)
      - Wadsworth Publishing Co. (Box 3a, Folder 24)
      - Wellesley College miscellaneous (Box 3a, Folder 24)
      - The Wild Fowl Trust (Box 3a, Folder 24)
      - H. W. Wilson Co. (Box 3a, Folder 24)
      - Winters, Yvor (correspondence from Robert Pinsky) (Box 3a, Folder 24)
      - Works (Box 3a, Folder 24)
      - Wright, Jay (Box 3a, Folder 24)
      - Yale Review (John Palmer) (Box 3a, Folder 24)
      - White House Salute to Poets and American Poetry (Box 3a, Folder 25)
    - A-B, misc:
      - Allen, Richard (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Antæus (Daniel Halpern) (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Baker, Herschel (Harvard) (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Bly, Robert (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Booth, Philip (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Bromwich, David (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - C-F, misc:
      - Canto Review of the Arts (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - Clampitt, Amy (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - Collier, Michael (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - Corey, Stephen (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - Cunningham, J.V. (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - Dennis, Carl (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - Feldman, Irving (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - Freedman, Bill (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - G-J, misc:
      - Galvin, Brendan (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Gibbons, Reginald (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Gleckner, Robert (UC Riverside) (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Groines, David (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Goldbarth, Albert (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Goldensohn, Barry (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Gregor, Deborah (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Guerard, A. (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Gunn, Thom (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Hall, Donald (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Halley, Anne (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Hillman, Brenda (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Hirsch, Edward (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Hollander, John (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Hughes, Olwyn (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Hughes, Shirley (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Helfgott Hyett, Barbara (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Hugo, Dick (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Janowitz, Phylis (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Jenkins, Joyce (Cody's Books) (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - K-L, misc:
      - Katrovas, Richard (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Kenikat Press (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Kenyon, Jane (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Kinzie, Mary (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Krynski, Magnus Jan (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Kumine, Maxine (Library of Congress) (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Lea, Sydney (New England Review) (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Logan, John (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - M, misc:
      - Mathias, John (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - Mack, Maynard (Yale) (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Manhattan Review (Phillip Fried) (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Mathis, Cleopatra (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Matthews, Bill (UW) (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Mazur, Gail (Blacksmith), and Michael (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - McClatchy, J.D. ("Sandy") (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - McGann, Jerome (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - McMichael, James (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Melone, Debbie (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Meredith, William (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Miser, Thomas (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Moffett, Judy (University of Pennsylvania) (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Moffett, Ken (Museum of Fine Arts, Boston) (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Molesworth, Charles (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Morgan, Frederick (The Hudson Review) (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Morris, John (Washington University) (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Moss, Howard (The New Yorker) (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Murphy, Romaine (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - N-O, misc:
      - Nemerov, Howard (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - The New England Review (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - The New Republic (Ann Hulbert) (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - The New Yorker (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - Oates, Joyce Carol (The Ontario Review) (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - Olds, Sharon (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - P, misc:
      - Peck, John (and Ellen) (Box 15, Folder 8)
      - Pinsky: Ellen, Nicole, and Caroline (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - Pack, Robert (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - Pastan, Linda (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - Pochada, Elizabeth (The Nation) (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - Pollens, David (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - Preyer, Robert (Brandeis) (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - Procopiow, Norma (University of Maryland) (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - Prunty, Wyatt (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - Pullin, William (Harcourt Brace and World/Jovanich Inc.) (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - R-S, misc:
      - Ray, David (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - Reeve, Franklin (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - Rosenberg, L. M. (SUNY Binghampton) (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - Ruark, Gibbons (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - Ryan, Michael (Princeton) (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - Sadoff, Ira (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - Salter, Mary Jo (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - Sandeen, Ernest (Box 15, Folder 11)